veteransunited.com 2018-06-22

# Privacy and Security Policy - Veterans United Home Loans

**Veterans United Home Loans is not endorsed or sponsored by the Department of Veterans Affairs or any government agency.**

## Consumer Privacy Notice

FACTS  | 

**WHAT DOES VETERANS UNITED HOME LOANS DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**  
  
---|---  
Why?  | 

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.   
  
What?  | 

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security Number and Credit Scores 
  * Income and Assets 
  * Employment Information and Credit History 

How?  |  All financial companies need to share customers' personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their personal information; the reasons Veterans United Home Loans chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.   
Reasons we can share your personal information  |  Does Veterans United Home Loans share?  |  Can you limit this sharing?   
---|---|---  
For our everyday business purposes - such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), responds to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus  | Yes | No  
For our marketing purposes - to offer our products and services to you | Yes | No  
For joint marketing with other financial companies | No | We Don't Share  
For our affiliates' everyday business purposes - information about your transactions and experiences | Yes | No  
For our affiliates' everyday business purposes - information about your creditworthiness | Yes | Yes  
For our affiliates to market to you | Yes | Yes  
For nonaffiliates to market to you | No | We Don't Share  
To limit our sharing  | 

  * Call 855-857-3933 — our menu will prompt you through your choices, or
  * Visit us online: [VeteransUnited.com/opt-out/](https://www.veteransunited.com/opt-out/)

**Please note:**  
If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice. However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.   
  
---|---  
Questions?  |  Call **1-800-884-5560** or go to [VeteransUnited.com/privacy](https://www.veteransunited.com/privacy/)  
---|---  
Who we are   
---  
**Who is providing this notice?** |  **Veterans United Home Loans**  
What we do   
**How does Veterans United Home Loans protect my personal information?** | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized accessand use, we use security measures that comply with federal law.These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.   
  
**How does Veterans United Home Loans collect my personal information?** | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you 

  * Apply for a loan or give us your income information 
  * Provide employment information or show your government-issued ID 
  * Give us your contact information 

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.   
  
**Why can't I limit all sharing?** | 

Federal law gives you the right to limit only 

  * sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes — information about your creditworthiness 
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you 
  * sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you 

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.   
  
**What happens when I limit sharing for an account I hold jointly with someone else?** | 

Your choices will apply to everyone on your account.   
  
Definitions   
**Affiliates** | 

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * Our affiliates include companies with a Veterans United, Military United, and Mortgage Research Center name; and nonfinancial companies such as Veterans United Realty. 

**Nonaffiliates** | 

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * Veterans United Home Loans does not share with nonaffiliates so they can market to you. 

**Joint marketing** | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you. 

  * Veterans United Home Loans does not jointly market. 

Other important information   
  
**Vermont Residents –** Except as permitted by law, we will not share information we collect about you with nonaffiliates or affiliates. 

**California Residents –** Except as permitted by law, we will not share information we collect about you with nonaffiliates or joint marketing partners while you are a resident of California. 

**Nevada Residents –** Call 1-855-857-3933 to be placed on our Do-Not-Call list. For more information, mail Veterans United Home Loans Call Center, 1400 Veterans United Dr., Columbia, MO 65203 or email privacy@vu.com. You may also contact the Bureau of Consumer Protection, Office of the Nevada Attorney General, 555 E. Washington Ave., Suite 3900, Las Vegas, NV 89101, call 702-486-3132, or email DBCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us. This notice is provided pursuant to state law.   
  
Click here to download a PDF copy of this Privacy Notice.

California Residents click here to download a PDF copy of the California Privacy Notice.

## Online Privacy Notice

  1. ### We Respect Your Privacy

Your privacy matters to us and we recognize the importance of keeping your information secure. Below, you will find details about our privacy policies and how your information is used. 

This Online Privacy Notice applies to this Veterans United Home Loans website. We encourage you to review this policy to better understand how information we collect is used to provide you with exceptional service. 

  2. ### What We Collect

We collect two types of information through this site: Personal and Non-Personal.

    1. #### **Personal Information**

Personal Information means personally identifiable information such as information you provide via forms, surveys, applications or other online fields including name, postal or email addresses, telephone, fax or mobile numbers, or account numbers. 

We may use Personal Information to: 

      1. to respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests; 

      2. to inform you about important information regarding the Site, products or services for which you apply or may be interested in applying for, or in which you are already enrolled, changes to terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information; 

      3. to deliver marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you, including, ads or offers tailored to you; 

      4. to personalize your experience on the Site; 

      5. for business purposes, including data analysis, audits, developing and improving products and services, enhancing the Site, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns; 

      6. for risk control, for fraud detection and prevention, to comply with laws and regulations, and to comply with other legal process and law enforcement requirements; 

    2. #### **Non-Personal Information**

We also collect Non-Personal information which includes, but is not limited to: your IP address, referral data, the web pages you view while visiting our site and your interactions with those pages. 

      1. We use this information to improved our site and better accommodate our visitors. 

      2. We utilize "cookies" throughout our site to improve your experience and to help us understand our visitors' needs. A "cookie" is a small text file that contains your anonymous information and is transferred onto your computer where it is stored, and then allows the website administrator to identify your computer and learn about how you use our web site. A "cookie" will not allow a web site to learn any personally identifiable information, like your name or address, that you otherwise would have disclosed. We use cookie information to identify and correct errors on our site and to determine the popularity of pages and to provide you with an excellent resource for mortgage information on the internet.

      3. We collect other site usage information via Google Analytics and Google's DoubleClick cookie to serve ads over time based on a user's prior visits to our website. You may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt out page or you may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

      4. We use FullStory.com to collect information regarding your use of our site, including pages visited, links clicked, non-sensitive text entered, and mouse movements, as well as information more commonly collected such as your IP address, referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider. FullStory.com does not collect or store your interactions with any form inputs that could be used to personally identify you. Data is stored by FullStory.com for up to 60 days after your web session. You may opt out of this usage tracking by clicking [here](https://www.fullstory.com/optout). 

      5. We use Mixpanel to collect site usage information, including your Operating System, IP, browser information, language, as well as interaction information including clicks, pages visted, and time on site, to improve our user experience. You may opt out of Mixpanel tracking by clicking [here](https://mixpanel.com/optout/). 

      6. **California "Do Not Track" Disclosures:** While some Internet browsers have the ability to specify privacy preferences to websites, including requests not to track your usage and browsing history, Veterans United Home Loans websites do not currently respond to these signals and may continue track your activity on this website and use gathered information as provided in this policy. 

  3. ###  How We Use Your Submitted Information 

    1. As a result of submitting your telephone number and your request to receive more information on a loan, you will receive a call from a Home Loan Specialist. You may be contacted directly by phone and/or email as a result of your request, even if the number you supplied is on the National Do Not Call registry. If, however, after you have submitted your information to us and you no longer wish to be contacted at the phone numbers provided, you may instruct us to place you on our internal "do not call" list by calling us at 1-800-884-5560. 

    2. You may choose what information to provide us. You may choose to withhold certain information, but this may affect your ability to use certain features of our website. We encourage consumers to disclose all pertinent information so we can provide a high level of customer service and offer the best products for you. 

    3. Federal and state laws require us to maintain certain loan qualification forms for set periods of time. In order to comply, we may be unable to delete certain information from our systems once you supply it to us. We make significant efforts to protect this information. 

    4. Veterans United Home Loans may periodically send you complimentary materials including newsletters, commercial offers, instructional videos or other information if you choose to provide us an email address. By providing your email address or submitting a request for more information that includes your email address, you have opted to receive these materials from us. If you desire to stop receiving these materials, please email [customer_service@veteransunited.com](mailto:customer_service@veteransunited.com) with the specific request. 

    5. For additional information on how Veterans United Home Loans makes use of the Personal Information you submit to us, please see our Consumer Privacy Notice. 

  4. ###  How We Share your Information 

    1. We may be required to disclose certain personal information resulting from a properly served request from a federal or state law enforcement or other governmental agency as a result of a subpoena, court order, in order to exercise our legal rights, to protect our company or employees from threats or fraud, to protect us from legal claims, or as otherwise required by law. We may raise or waive any legal rights available to us. This information may also be disclosed in the event of a merger or sale of the company, an asset sale, or the unlikely event of bankruptcy. 

  5. ###  Opt-Out Provisions 

    1. Once you submit your information to Veterans United Home Loans it may not be retracted. You will be contacted by a representative after you submit a request through our site or an affiliate site. 

    2. We may disclose any of the personal information that we collect from our customer or former customer to non-affiliated third party entities as permitted by federal and state law. 

    3. If you wish to prevent all websites from tracking your website usage data via FullStory.com, you may opt out by navigating to [https://fullstory.com/optout](https://www.fullstory.com/optout) and clicking "Opt out of FullStory." Opting out will create a cookie that tells FullStory.com to turn off recording. The presence of this cookie is required to continue opting out, so if you clear your browsing cookies, you will need to opt-out again 

    4. If you wish to prevent all websites from tracking your website usage data via Mixpanel, you may opt out by navigating to <https://mixpanel.com/optout/> and selecting "Yes, I would like to opt out." and clicking "Save." 

    5. We comply with all relevant state and federal laws regarding the safeguarding of your personal information. Maintaining the security of your information is a top priority at Veterans United Home Loans, so please contact us with any questions or concerns that you have regarding this policy. 

**WE DO NOT DISCLOSE ANY NON-PUBLIC PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION ABOUT YOU TO ANYONE FOR ANY PURPOSE THAT IS NOT SPECIFICALLY PERMITTED BY LAW**

    6. We restrict access to your stored non-public personal identifiable information to those employees that need to know this information in order to provide our services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations in order to guard your information against unauthorized access. 

  6. ### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA):

    1. This site is intended for individuals age 18 and older. Children under the age of 13 should not use this site, and are expressly prohibited from using our services. 

  7. ### Our Secure System Protects You

    1. To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, Veterans United Home Loans uses physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards. Nevertheless, no system can be completely secure, and you should not expect that your information will remain protected. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, human error, or a number of other factors may compromise the security of your information. As a consumer, you should always safeguard your personal information and protect yourself from potential identify fraud. 

  8. ###  General Policy Provisions 

    1. The policies and practices described in this disclosure are subject to change, but we will communicate any such changes to you as required by law. We encourage you to periodically review our privacy policy for any changes. 

    2. You may receive copies of this privacy policy as well as the terms and conditions by sending an email detailing your request to [customer_service@veteransunited.com](mailto:customer_service@veteransunited.com) or by sending a written request to: 

Customer Service  
Veterans United Home Loans  
1400 Veterans United Dr.  
Columbia, MO 65203 

Call **1-800-884-5560** to speak with a Home Loan Specialist.

## Transaction Communications

During your homebuying experience, Veterans United Home Loans works with a variety of third parties and affiliates to promote a better homebuying experience. Many of our clients choose to use the services of a real estate agent. While the choice to use a real estate agent during the transaction is an individual one and is not a condition for service, Veterans United Home Loans is uniquely positioned to work hand in hand with an agent if you choose to do so. 

Your real estate agent works to help you throughout your homebuying process, from shopping for the perfect home, all the way to helping you at the closing table. To promote a high level of service to you, Veterans United may provide your real estate agent with a mobile application known as AgentEdge. The AgentEdge app serves as a tool for your agent in order to provide transparency and encourage momentum during the loan process. We share specific information with your agent so that he or she may better understand your needs. This includes but not limited to: 

  * Your contact information, including phone and email.
  * Your loan officer and his/her team’s contact information
  * How much you are preapproved for and the ability to generate a preapproval letter on your behalf
  * Ability to upload documents, such as purchase contract
  * Receive notifications when your file reaches important milestones

Veterans United Home Loans will not communicate information to your real estate agent unless we believe they need to know the information to perform their duties as your agent. Veterans United clients may opt out of providing their agent's access to the app at any time. Clients may contact [customerservice@veteransunited.com](mailto:customerservice@veteransunited.com) or alert their designated loan officer that they would prefer to not share the information with their agent. By submitting your information, you agree to allow Veterans United Home Loans to release transaction information to your real estate agent, if you choose to work with one. 

**Veterans United Home Loans (Last Updated: December 21, 2016)**

Speak with a Home Loan Specialist today 

Representatives Available 24/7 to Better Serve Troops Overseas 

A VA approved lender; Not endorsed or sponsored by the Dept. of Veterans Affairs or any government agency.
